<sub>




<lcn>

<p>
If at all possible, every Padawan should be
paired with a Mentor so as to provide the proper
environment for growth at this stage.
However, it is possible for a Padawan to be in a situation
in which nobody is available to serve as Mentor -
or worse, in which nobody who can be trusted
is available for that purpose.
</p>

<p>
Unfortunately, no advice that could be given
to a Padawan in that position would be as good as
pairing zim with someone qualified to be zir Mentor
- but any advice that is better than nothing-at-all
should not be left out here.
</p>

<p>
Even without a mentor, there will be some resources
available to many Padawans.
These resources may come in the form of books, in the form of
online classes, and possibly other forms as well.
The first thing for a Masterless Padawan to do is to
make full use of these resources at whatever point in zir
training they are called for.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
The second thing for a Mentorless Padawan to do is to exercise
wisdom and humility in applying zir skills to real-life
situations.
It can be tough to navigate the fine line between being too
timid to gain any real experience on one hand and on the other
being reckless and exposing zirself to needless amounts of any
kind of risk.
</p>

<p>
Do not be shy about asking for help in discernment as
you walk this delicate path.
Even if there is no Mentor to provide consistent
guidance at this stage that is no excuse not to make use
of it when you have the ability in a specific instance
to receive guidance - as longas your source is
trustworthy to provide guidance in the particular
context for which it is provided.
</p>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
The third thing for a Mentorless Padawan to do
is to be mindful of what zie has learned about
tuning in to the Force and receiving it's guidance.
This is, of course, something every Padawan needs
to do - indeed any Jedi at any stage in zir training -
but it has special significance for the Mentorless
Padawan.
</p>

<p>
By the time of having graduated from an Initiate, and
well before that as a matter of fact, a Jedi will have
learned some skills in attuning to the Force.
This set of skills will increase through the Padawan
stage of training - and for that matter, for the entire
life-process of a Jedi's training.
These skills are skills that every Padawan needs experience with.
</p>

<p>
Every Padawan must
attune to the Force and be so
guided because the skills for doing this are among
the skills that a Padawan is supposed to be gaining
experience in.
But for a Masterless Padawan,
this can also be vital in knowing how, or even if to apply
a specific skill to a specific situation -
as well as to knowing what must be learned next in zir
training.
</p>

</lcn>


</sub>
