<sub >

<lcn>

<p>
After that, the applicant may enter the second
phase of preparation
by making before the Council, or before it's
designated representation,
temporary vows for the three commitments
binding until the end of the following week.
During this second phase of reparation,
the applicant is to walk the Jedi path under the
supervision of the Council.
However, the Council will remain the applicant's
sole connection to the metatemple beyond what
is also accessible to the general public.
</p>

<p>
At some point during thie first full week of this
phase of preparation, the applicant may be
permitted to renew zir vows, extending them by
another week, and so forth.
However, not until the third full week at earliest
may the applicant switch from weekly renewal
of zir vows to monthly renewals -
and extending zir vows to the end of the following
month must not be done until the ides of the current month.
And never during this phase of preparation
may the applicant be allowed
to extend zir vows by more
than one month at a time.
</p>

<p>
Diring this phase, the Council must, in the context
of the applicant walking the Jedi path, assess that
applicant's fitness and
readiness to be a part of the metatemple.
It is the duty of the Council to welcome those
who have potential of becoming great Jedi,
and to do so
even to the point of recognizing such potential
in applicants who come in a very coarse raw-state
-
while at the same time
turning away those who would only fill the metatemple
with faux Jedi.
Yet let the Council guard vigilantly
against any tendency to make decisions based on
irrelevant criteria such as race, gender,
sexual orientation, religion, or anything else
of that sort.
</p>

<extx cls="note">

<p>
Some may criticize the mention of religion as
an irrelevant criterion and ask
"What if there is a religion that is known
to have tennets in conflict with the Jedi path?"
</p>

<p>
The reason why religion is nonetheless considered
to be an irrelevant criterion is this: What does it
mean for a religion to be "known" to have
such tennets?
It can mean a number of things.
It can mean that the religion as a certain member
of the Council understands it has such tennets.
It can mean that some body who is perceived
by someone in the Council to authoritatively
speak on behalf
of that religion espouses such tennets.
It can mean a number of things --
but all that matters is whether
the religion as understood and followed by
that particular applicant
has tennets in conflict with the Jedi path.
</p>

<p>
If all measures of what a religion is "known" to
be like suggest that it has tennets in conflict
with the Jedi path - that is of no bearing if
that applicant's version of that religion
does not share those conflicting traits.
</p>

</extx>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
The Council should specify an amount of time
that this phase is to take for first-time applicants
-- an amount of time that is long enough to assure
that applicants can be familiar with this entire
Rule and long enough that, barring unusual circumstances,
the Council should be able to assess all applicants - yet
not much longer than these requirements dictate.
Let this amount of time be well-known - and though
it may need to be adjusted from time to time, let
it not be changed erratically.
</p>

<p>
Generally speaking, it is the duty of the Council
to render a decision within this specified amount
of time.
In the case of an applicant for whom
the Council is, for a specific reason, unable to do this -
let the Council
articulate this reason and meet with the applicant to
discuss the matter.
Otherwise, at least for those who would be
entering the metatemple for the first time
or who have no history of disgraceful departure
of any kind,
a decision by the Council must be made by the
time the designated time period is up.
</p>

<p>
On the other hand, those who have separated
from the metatemple
during the duration of their vows without
the extreme justification required for doing so,
or who upon departing even with such
justification ceased to at even
follow the Jedi path separately from the
metatemple while their vows were still in force,
or who have been turned away
due to inexcusable behavior against which
lesser recourses had proven inadequte --
let their re-admittance be allowed with greater
trepidation each time that they enter after
such a disgraceful exit.
Let this re-admittance be made more reluctant
after each disgraceful departure of this nature
until eventually - generally after the third
departure of such disgrace - the one in question
be denied re-admittance altogether.
</p>

</lcn>

</sub>