<sub >

<lcn>

<p>
After that, the applicant may enter the <i>second</i>
phase of preparation
by making before the Council, or before it's
designated representation,
temporary vows for the three commitments
binding until the end of the following week.
During this second phase of reparation,
the applicant is to walk the Jedi path under the
supervision of the Council.
However, the Council will remain the applicant's
sole connection to the metatemple beyond what
is also accessible to the general public.
</p>

<p>
At some point during thie first full week of this
phase of preparation, the applicant may be
permitted to renew zir vows, extending them by
another week, and so forth.
However, not until the third full week at earliest
may the applicant switch from weekly renewal
of zir vows to monthly renewals -
and extending zir vows to the end of the <i>following</i>
month must not be done until the <i>ides</i> of the <i>current</i> month.
And <i>never</i> during this phase of preparation
may the applicant be allowed
to extend zir vows by more
than one month at a time.
</p>

<p>
Diring this phase, the Council must, in the context
of the applicant <i>walking</i> the Jedi path, assess that
applicant's fitness and
readiness to be a part of the metatemple.
</p>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
The Council should specify an amount of time
that this phase is to take for first-time applicants
-- an amount of time that is long enough to assure
that applicants can be familiar with this entire
Rule and long enough that, barring unusual circumstances,
the Council should be able to assess all applicants - yet
not much longer than these requirements dictate.
Let this amount of time be well-known - and though
it may need to be adjusted from time to time, let
it not be changed <i>erratically</i>.
</p>

<p>
Generally speaking, it is the duty of the Council
to render a decision within this specified amount
of time.
In the case of an applicant for whom
the Council is, for a specific reason, unable to do this -
let the Council
<i>articulate</i> this reason and meet with the applicant to
discuss the matter.
Otherwise, at least for those who would be
entering the metatemple for the first time
or who have no history of disgraceful departure
of any kind,
a decision by the Council must be made by the
time the designated time period is up.
</p>

<p>
On the other hand, those who have separated
from the metatemple
during the duration of their vows without
the extreme justification required for doing so,
or who upon departing even <i>with</i> such
justification ceased to at even
follow the Jedi path <i>separately</i> from the
metatemple while their vows were still in force,
or who have been turned away
due to inexcusable behavior against which
lesser recourses had proven inadequte --
let their re-admittance be allowed with greater
trepidation each time that they enter after
such a disgraceful exit.
Let this re-admittance be made more reluctant
after each disgraceful departure of this nature
until eventually - generally after the third
departure of such disgrace - the one in question
be denied re-admittance altogether.
</p>

<extx cls="plch">

<p>
More abuse-proofing language is needed here.
</p>

<p>
First, we don't want to allow the Council to
string an applicant along indefinitely -- or to
in <i>general</i> be discriminatory by stringing
an applicant along <i>any</i> longer
than they otherwise would
by an invalid criterion.
On the other hand - the Council needs to
be assured <i>adequate</i> time to make a
<i>proper</i> assessment of the applicant.
</p>

<p>
The other thing ---
the Council has the <i>responsibility</i>,
and therefore must have also the <i>authority</i>,
to use <i>both</i> phases of the preparation period to
screen out the kinds of applicants who would only
end up flooding the metatemple with Faux Jedi
(like those discussed in the chapter labeled <dcn>Avoid Straying from the Path</dcn>.
However, we don't want to allow the Council
to <i>abuse</i> this authority by accepting and
rejecting applicants based on <i>prejudice</i>.
</p>

<p>
It would <i>also</i> be nice if some language
could be added to dissuade the Council from
<i>prematurely</i> giving up on applicants who
are rough-around-the-edges but still <i>very</i>
capable of being <i>reformed</i> and turning out
to be very <i>strong</i> Jedi.
And back to the <i>first</i> issue mentioned in
this note - the Council may need a <i>little</i>
more time with <i>such</i> applicants to assess
them -- but even <i>these</i> applicants, there
should be a <i>limit</i> to how long they can be
strung along.
At some point, even those rough-around-the-edges
applicants, the Council must come to a conclusion
as to whether they are <i>capable</i> of becoming
<i>serious</i> Jedi.
</p>

</extx>

</lcn>

</sub>