<sect>
<title>On the Jedi Code</title>

<lcn>

<stnz>
<l>There is no emotion, there is peace.</l>
<l>There is no ignorance, there is knowledge.</l>
<l>There is no passion, there is serenity.</l>
<l>There is no chaos, there is harmony.</l>
<l>There is no death, there is the Force.</l>
</stnz>

<p>
This is the mantra of the Jedi.
However, contrary to a common misconception, it is not the
entirety of the Jedi Code - but a mantra to invoke
the Code in the mind of a Jedi practitioner.
It can serve as a very useful tool to bring the Code
or any aspect of it to consciousness - but for it
to make proper sense nonetheless requires further
study and understanding of the Code.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
One difficulty lies in that there is no single
document that authoritatively details the entirety
of the Jedi Code.
Rather, there are several sources which contain
part of the Code - none containing all of it in
it's fullness.
Furthering this difficulty is that even as far
as an Introductory Rule for the study of the Jedi
Code, there is no standard one for the entire
Jedi community.
</p>

<p>
In the fictional <dcn>Star Wars</dcn> universe,
the term "Jedi" refers to a specific order
- or more exactly any of a series of orders of
which only one existed at any specific time,
each of which was built from what was left
after the destruction of the previous one.
Though other orders of that archetype existed
in the <dcn>Star Wars</dcn> universe, the term
"Jedi" did not apply to them.
</p>

<p>
By contrast, in our reality, the term "Jedi"
refers not to a specific order, or even to one
specific order at any given time, but to an entire
community of orders striving to emulate the same
archetype.
Each order might have it's own Introductory Rule
in the study of the Jedi Code.
If we restrict the use of the term "Jedi" only
to those orders that are actually faithful in
their effort to emulate the archetype (and a
very strong
case could definitely be made for using the
term in such a restrictive manner) then all
those rules point toward the ultimate Jedi Code,
but none of them is the full, living Jedi Code itself.
It would not be so even if we had the text of
the Introductory Rule of the fictional Jedi
of the <dcn>Star Wars</dcn> universe.
</p>

<p>
There is not, nor would it be reasonable to
wish that there be, any single document
that one can read to learn the entirety of
the Jedi Code.
As with every other aspect of Jedi training,
learning the Jedi Code is a lifelong process.
</p>

<extx cls = "docbg">
<title>Not Just One Jedi's Views</title>

<p>
Even if the term "Jedi" is restricted only to those orders that
are actually faithful in their effort to emulate the archetype,
different groups of Jedi (and even different Jedi within
the same groups) will have different interpretations
and understandings regarding the Jedi Code.
While some inevitability exists to this documeint
reflecting the perspectives of it's authorship,
effort has been made to minimize this -
even to the point of (when necessary) starting
online discussions related to matters discussed in this Rule.
</p>

<p>
Early on - when the size of the Midnight Academy was just
one member, such discussions were conducted on various
Internet-based Jedi forums.
Later on, the Midnight Academy grew to be larger than
just one person - and the Rule was adopted as the
primary handbook of the Midnight Academy,
which made it permissible to include text
specific to the Midnight Academy.
Ever since, the policy has been to announce any changes
under consideration to the main forum of the Midnight
Academy
and to allow a period of discussion before
integrating the proposed changes into the official
branches of the Rule.
In the event of <i>silence</i>, the window would
generally last a few days before the silence would be
interpreted as meaning that nobody has anything
to say.
</p>

</extx>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
The absence of any document containing the
entirety of the Jedi Code is not merely
an accident - nor even a consequence of
the fact that it would take more wisdom than
has been possessed by anyone who ever had
the time to write about the Jedi Code.
Rather, it is inherently impossible to fit
all of the Jedi Code into writing.
References to and descriptions of the Jedi
Code can be put into writing - but there is
a strong aspect of the Code that can only
be learned by practicing it, by integrating
it into one's life.
</p>

<p>
By living the Jedi Code and making it a
part of your everyday life you not only
learn the Jedi Code at a level that you
never can just by reading about it.
Living the Jedi Code day to day over time
makes it a part of you.
It is this that makes you a true Jedi.
All other Jedi skills are mere add-ons.
</p>

<p>
Make no mistake. Those add-on skills are
not unimportant.
It is a violation of the Jedi Code
to willfully neglect these skills.
As the mantra states:
"There is no ignorance, there is knowledge".
Describing them as "add-ons" merely means
that they are not what <i>defines</i> a
true Jedi - and more importantly, that they
are not a part of the foundation, but rather,
part of the edifice that is built <i>upon</i>
the foundation.
</p>

</lcn>



<lcn>

<p>
It is making the Jedi Code a part of you
that will make you a true Jedi and give
you the foundation for everything else.
This Introductory Rule is a tool to
help you do exactly that.
It's chapters are divided into daily
lessons for this purpose - and the length
of these daily lessons is not formulated
with print-length or word-count as
the primary concern,
but rather, with digestibility in mind.
This way, each lesson will give you something
to engrain within you on a particular day
without giving enough to overwhelm in this
process.
</p>

<p>
So each day, read, study that day's lesson.
Meditate on it - and understand it.
Even journaling may help.
Many days, the lesson of that day will even
have a direct bearing on how you live that
very day - in which case it can benefit you
to pay extra attention to following the
lesson in your living that day as well.
</p>

<p>
For informational study, there is no
harm in reading more than one lesson
of this Rule a day - however, as far
as the process of engraining lessons
into yourself, focusing on one a day
is strongly advised - if not insisted upon.
May there be enough lessons in this Rule
that when you reach the end of the cycle
and start it again from the beginning,
you will be able to approach each lesson
with a fresh perspective rather than
as a repetitive thing.
</p>

<p>
This Rule strives to peg every part of the
Jedi Code onto a section of the Jedi Mantra.
However, this is not done out of any
delusion of the Jedi Mantra being the source
of the Jedi Code - nor out of the even more preposterous
notion that the Jedi Mantra is <i>itself</i>
the Jedi Code.
Those notions are not just misconceptions, but they
are very dangerous ones to one's Jedi training -
and therefore they must be most decisively banished
from any thought or consideration.
Rather, the reason why this Rule strives to
peg every part of the Jedi Code onto a section
of the Jedi Mantra is to increase the Jedi Mantra's
strength as a tool by which to remind
one's self of and center one's self on the Jedi Code.
</p>

</lcn>


</sect>