<sub>
<lcn>

<p>
There are, of course, three formats in which vows may be made or
extended.
These are the handwritten form, the witnessed form,
and the minor-extensive form.
Knowing the nature and limitations of these forms can help
determine which form is appropriate in any given occasion.
</p>

<p>
The first is the handwritten form - in which the Jedi
making the vows hand-writes the entire chapter of this
Rule in which the commitments of a Jedi are described
followed by the hand-written declaration: &quot;Knowing all
this, I, 'X', promise to uphold these commitments
to the metatemple
through the end of 'N'.&quot; - where 'X' is replaced
by the name of the Jedi taking those vows and 'N' is
replaced by the last time-period through which the vows
are to endure. Then, all pages save the last one must
be initialed and dated with the date on which the vows
are made - and the final page must be signed and dated
with that same date.
These pages must be scanned into the appropriate digital
form and as such provided to the metatemple's Membership
Officers - those being members of the metatemple
charged by the Prime Council with the task of
keeping membership records, an appointment which if
possible should be given to multiple members so as to provide the
safety that only redundant storage of data can provide.
</p>

<extx cls="note">
<p>
The words "to the metatemple" were not present in the
original form of the declaration, but added on later.
And specifically, the words "the metatemple"
can be replaced by text that specifically
identifies the metatemple, such as "the Midnight Academy"
- and ultimately must be whatever words the Prime Council
dictates be in that place.
</p>

<p>
Also - it should go without saying that the version
of the chapter on the commitments made by a Jedi who's
text is contained in the signed vow does not
need to include the extended text, but only
the primary text.
</p>
</extx>

<p>
The second is the witnessed form - resembling the
handwritten form except that it instead of being
hand-written, it is printed from a standard form
provided by the metatemple in which 'X' and 'N'
are blank-spaces to be filled with the appropriate
contents.
In lieu of handwriting, to assure that the document
is not signed in ignorance of it's contents,
the signature of the Jedi who is making the vows
must be followed by the declaration:
&quot;We, the undersigned, witness that 'X'  made these vows
orally and by signature on the date 'M'.&quot; where 'M'
is a blank-space filled with the date on which the
vows are signed.
After this, it must be signed by three members of
the metatemple who have witnessed the said event,
and who are trusted by the Prime Council for this purpose.
Again, these pages must be scanned into the appropriate digital
form and as such provided to the metatemple's Membership
Officers.
</p>

<p>
Any hand-written vows as well any witnessed vows must
remain a part of the respective Jedi's Current Membership
Records until the end of the very last half-year period into which they
extend, even if that Jedi permits zir vows to expire
before that half-year period ends.
Furthermore, if such vows are initially signed during the last three months
of that half-year period, they must be kept in like manner for the
following half-year period as well.
</p>

</lcn>
<lcn>

<p>
The third is the minor-extensive form - a form that
may not be used for initial vows, but only to
extend existing vows.
Furthermore, the minor-extensive form may not extend
vows into a new half-year period - that is, past the
start of a new January or the start of a new July
- unless there are hand-written or witnessed vows
that were were initially
signed by that Jedi during the last three months of the previous
half-year period.
As with the witnessed form of the vows, the
minor-extensive form is likewise printed from
a standard form provided by the metatemple in which
the custom parts are blank-spaces filled in by pen
after the printing.
However, the method by which this form assures
that it is not signed in ignorance of it's contents
is that it must be kept in the membership records
together with the previous vows of either the
handwritten form or the witnessed form that brought
that Jedi's vows into the current half-year period.
</p>

<p>
To that end, in the minor-extensive form - after the
declaration of commitment, and before the signature,
the minor-extensive form must contain in the same
paragraph the declaration: &quot;My familiarity with
the contents of these vows are attested by the
vows I signed on 'L'.&quot; where 'L'
is a blank-space filled in pen with the date on which
the handwritten or witnessed vows that these
minor-extensive vows depend on were signed.
</p>

<p>
In general, it is sufficient that a copy the Current Membership Records
of a member of the metatemple be kept by all of the
metatemple's Membership Officers.
However, in the case of members of the Prime Council as well
as in the case of Membership Officers, it is essential
that also all members of the Prime Council keep a copy
of the Current Membership Records, as well as post them
online for all to see.
</p>

<extx cls = "note">
<p>
The purpose of the public display of the vows of the Membership
Officers and members of the Prime Council is that it can be possible
to take vows even at times when the membership of a metatemple
is too small to meaningfully take them within the community.
</p>
</extx>

</lcn>
</sub>
