<sect>
<title>On Living in the Moment</title>


<lcn>

<p>
Remember Yoda's observation about Luke Skywalker -
how he was always obsessed, fixated on the future
that he was headed toward to the point of neglecting
the moment that he was in at the present.
Even in his dealings up to that point with the
Jedi Master on Degobah, Luke's fixation on
where he was off to was an issue ---
constantly obsessed with his search for the
mysterious Yoda to the point that it never
occurred to him to ask the little green fellow
in front of him what his name was.
</p>

<p>
Had Luke bothered to ask the little green
creature his name -- he might have answered
right there and then that his name was "Yoda",
and Luke would have realized that he had found
the Jedi Master he sought.
</p>

<p>
Being obsessed with where you are going to the
point of total neglect of the moment you are in
right there and then can cause all kinds of
disasters -- from not knowing when you have
reached your destination - to not seeing the
clearest path to your destination even if you
<i>haven't</i> reached it.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
Fixation on the future, of course, is not
to be confused with proper, due regard for the
future.
Nor should anyone disregard the potential
future consequences of one's actions in
the name of <i>not</i> being fixated on
the future.
Rather, the admonition against fixation on
the future means seeing the future for what
it is - while recognizing that the immediate
actions one is to take are not in the future
any more than they are in the past, but rather,
they are in the present moment.
</p>

<p>
It also means that the present moment is
the environment that one must interact with
right now. Even if your present actions
affect the environment of the future --
it will not be until later that you actually
<i>interact</i> with that future environment.
Therefore, let no future planning interfere
with awareness of the present - and let it not
interfere with focusing on one's present
actions either.
</p>

<p>
If you fail to heed this admonition,
you run increased risk of even allowing
your obsession of the future to <i>paralyze</i>
your actions in the present moment!
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
Being present in the moment also involves
barriers that must be set with the past.
We must always learn from our past -- both
from our triumphs and from our failures
-- both from our mistakes and from times
that we made the right move.
However, regret and loathing about the
past are a waste of energy at best -- and
they have the potential of being
the seed of great darkness, which is much
worse.
</p>

<p>
Learn from the past -- but move on from it.
The past is gone.
The present moment is now here -- and you must
attend to it now before it, too, slips into the
realm of the past.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
Fuming, crying, or otherwise harming
your soul over the past, are you?
Pause then and remind yourself that the
past can no longer be changed.
The future is in flux. The past, however, is
now only a source of lessons.
Let not baggage from the past be the basis
for you damaging your soul in the present.
</p>

<p>
The past is gone. For right now,
only the present is here.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
So when concern of the future overwhelms you
-- be present in the moment.
When anger or regret regarding the past that can
no longer change seizes you
-- be present in the moment.
And when your fears and worries paralyze you
from what you need to do immediately
-- be present in the moment.
</p>

<p>
Peg this onto the third verse of the Jedi Mantra:
"There is no passion, there is serenity."
</p>

</lcn>


</sect>
