<sect>
<title>On the Metatemple</title>

<lcn>

<p>
For a very long time, there has been much talk
in the Jedi community about building a vast
Jedi Temple somewhere so that Jedi might live
communally there, that their training be enhanced by
one another's presence.
While there are definite reasons why it might be seen
as a nice thing for the Jedi community to have, excessive
focus on it's pursuit can seriously
undermine the Jedi discipline.
</p>

<p>
The correct way to approach the construction
of such a Jedi Temple is to focus on our Jedi training
where we are, in the present moment, so that if and
when the Force reveals that it is time to build
such a temple, we will be ready.
In the mean time, let us support one another's training
through the network of a metatemple.
</p>

<p>
The very existence of a metatemple rests on
the understanding that any place where a Jedi lives
and trains is indeed a Jedi temple.
If nothing
else, then at least a <vc>microtemple</vc>
- that is, a Jedi temple large enough for extremely
few Jedi, even if just one Jedi.
The Jedi of a microtemple will use various means
of making the best of the situation of not
having the large community of a full-sized temple
to train with.
This can include the use of technology for purposes
that might not be as vital, or even needed
at all, for Jedi of a
larger temple.
</p>

<p>
One use of technology that can be especially
vital to a microtemple is the use of communications
technologies, such as the Internet, to be
part of a <vc>metatemple</vc> -
that is, a network of Jedi temples connected through
the fullest use of communications technology so as to
function as much as possible as a single larger
temple for the support of training.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
But let it never be forgotten that a metatemple
has no existence without it's member temples, down to
the smallest microtemple.
Every Jedi must, therefore, be fully mindful of the fact
that the entire temple in which zie resides, and not
just the communications equipment,
is part of the metatemple - and that zie must
maintain zir entire temple with due vigilance
- from the dojo, to the kitchen, to the dining area,
to the sleeping area - the entire residence.
</p>

<p>
Of course, should a Jedi live in a shared residence
with non-Jedi, then and only then might there be a
need to establish boundaries of the temple within
the residence.
If this is needed, then let it be done - even, if necessary,
contacting the Council for advisement.
</p>

</lcn>

</sect>
