<sect>
<title>On the Technical Council</title>

<lcn>

<p>
Let the metatemple establish a Technical Council,
so as to aid the member temples in setting up and using
their technology in a way that maximizes their participation
in the metatemple - and, in general, maximizes
their effectiveness as Jedi temples.
</p>

<p>
Let this Technical Council be an appropriate size for
dealing with the heaviest workload that can be reasonably
foreseen given the size of the metatemple,
whether that means that it have one memer or several members.
Should the number of Jedi in the metatemple qualified to
serve on the Technical Council be fewer than the number
required, or should that even be <i>close</i> to happening,
let <i>apprentice</i> members <i>also</i> be assigned
to the Technical Council.
</p>

<p>
Also, just as the Technical Council takes on apprentice
members for the training of new technical advisors,
let the <i>full</i> members of the Council <i>likewise</i>
train one another so that each become a more well-rounded
technical advisor.
</p>

</lcn>
<lcn>

<p>
To this end, should one member of the Technical Council
call upon another due to inability to confidently resolve
a specific issue, let not the first be dismissed to work
on another case or to do something else.
Rather, let the first stick around and even continue
actively <i>participating</i> in the case, so that <i>learning</i>
be derived from having to call upon another.
As a matter of fact, if <i>possible</i>,
let the <i>second</i> not even take <i>over</i> the
case from the first, but rather, let the second <i>guide</i>
the first through resolving the case <i>zirself</i>.
As the second line of the Jedi Mantra goes: "There is
no ignorance, there is knowledge".
</p>

<p>
And should a member of the Technical Council be in <i>doubt</i>
as to whether or not to call another - let zim be reminded
not to see weakness in not <i>already</i> being certain of the
answer - but <i>rather</i> to see <i>strength</i> in the eagerness
to <i>learn</i> - as <i>well</i> as strength in the commitment
to <i>verifying</i> that you are resolving the case as well as
you <i>hope</i> that you are doing.
</p>

<p>
And woe unto the technical advisor who latches on to a
pet-theory regarding a case and ignores facts or input
to the contrary of this pet-theory - or who even fails
to properly <i>check</i> these factors!
Let anyone who behaves in such a rash
and arrogant manner be
appropriately disciplined!
</p>

</lcn>

</sect>
