<sub>

<lcn>

<p>
The commitment to Jedi Perseverance means that the Jedi commits,
in the event of failure, to integrate that failure into
zir study and into zir life by learning whatever lessons
are to be taught by that failure and using those lessons
to strengthen zir walk along the Jedi path.
Through the commitment to Jedi Perseverance,
the Jedi commits to do this upon every failure,
no matter now many times zie fails along the path -
and to steer away from seeing these failures as
sources of discouragement by instead treating them
as sources of wisdom.
</p>

<p>
Also, as a general rule, through the commitment to Jedi Perseverance,
the Jedi commits to remain with the metatemple
for the duration of zir vows.
However, as there exists the potential for situations beyond
that Jedi's control that could prevent this from being done,
allowances must be made in such cases - though only
in such cases.
</p>

<p>
For starters, a failure in communications technology
might cause such a tremendous disruption in communication
as to render that Jedi's participation in the metatemple
no longer much of a reality.
However, there is also the possibility that a corruption
in the metatemple, or an ethical blind-spot affecting the
Council, renders the metatemple so toxic that
to remain with it is in conflict of authentically
following the Jedi Path.
In such situations, a departure may not be
the fault of the Jedi who departs, even in the face
of this commitment.
</p>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
That said, even in those situations, departure
from the metatemple must not be done too readily.
It must be with great trepidation even then that
a Jedi depart.
It must not be done unless it is completely beyond that
Jedi's power to resolve that situation - unless
the only means available by which to do this are
fraught with true and significant hazard.
It also must not be done unless the toxicity is so significant
that it is truly impossible to follow the Jedi path
while remaining with the metatemple.
Through the commitment to Jedi Perseverance, the Jedi
commits, even in those situations, only to depart
when any effort to make it possible to remain is
proven to be futile.
</p>

<p>
Also, even when such a situation compels a Jedi to depart
despite still being under vows,
it does not release that Jedi from zir
commitments made as a Jedi - but merely permit that Jedi
to fulfil those commitments in an environment separate
from the metatemple.
This is because even though the metatemple and that Jedi's
link to it are beyond zir locus of control,
and as such, the potential exists for situations
that would deprive that Jedi of the ability to
fulfil zir commitments while there
- zir resolve
to follow the Jedi path is always well within
zir locus of control,
and therefore can be upheld even when that Jedi is deprived
of the metatemple.
</p>

</lcn>

</sub>
