<sub>




<lcn>

<p>
The Sith are the ultimate in Jedi training
gone-wrong.
Sometimes someone becomes a Sith because they
were of ill-will from the start -
yet for some reason, they were not screened
out and received Jedi training anyway.
However, quite often, it is not like
this at all - rather, it is a result of
someone making a wrong-turn in their training
and never getting back on the right track.
</p>

<p>
The Sith uses the dark emotions to access
the Force - and thus cultivates these dark emotions
so as to continue being able to do so.
Sometimes this is even how the downward spiral
to Sithdom begins.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
While the Jedi seeks unity with the Force, harmony
with the Universe - the Sith seeks power and thinks
of the Force largely as a means to that end.
Sometimes this, too, can be the gateway to Sithdom
when a Jedi in training refuses to accept
one of the immutables of life.
</p>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
In the fictional <dcn>Star Wars</dcn> universe,
the Sith all carry red lightsabers, have
names beginning with "Darth", and in-general
display full cognizance of the fact that they
are Sith.
In real life, not all Sith are aware that they
are Sith - that the path that they are on is
no longer the Jedi path.
Many think that they have merely tempered the
Jedi path with "reality".
In truth, though, what they have mixed in is
a one-sided and distorted extract from reality.
They exaggerate the difficulty of the Jedi Path -
and while that difficulty is in fact real, their
elevation of that difficulty elevates it to the
level of impossibility, or at least impracticality.
That and/or they are way too dismissive of
the other side of the equation -
that being that while the Jedi path is not always
the most expedient way of doing things,
there will be serious consequences of
straying from the path because of this.
<!-- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ZNLA7t-gIY -->
As Master Yoda said: "If you choose the quick and easy
path as Vader did, you will become an agent of evil."
</p>

<p>
The Sith fancy themselves to be wiser than the Jedi.
Nonetheless, it is they who are the foolish ones.
</p>

</lcn>

</sub>
