<sect>
<title>On the Dark Side</title>

<lcn>

<p>
There are, of course, no two separate entities known as
the "Light Side of the Force" and the "Dark
Side of the Force". No - there is only
the Force. The Dark Side of the Force is
a reference to the darker inclinations
of the Force -- the potential for
corruption in the Force.
</p>

<p>
This corruption is what happens when
the Force is accessed through the darker
emotions of fear, anger, hate - even
pain.
To avoid falling to the dark side - one
must learn how to dispel and dissipate
these darker emotions without channeling
them into the Force -
and also how to access the Force without
resorting to use of these darker emotions
in doing so.
</p>

</lcn>

<lcn>

<p>
One thing that leaves someone susceptible
to such dark emotions
is the unreasonable attachment to things that are beyond
our power to assure
- things that are not truly our own.
It is the way of the Jedi to let go of
our attachments to such
weak and insecure things -
freeing ourselves of their bonds.
</p>

<p>
We may never reach perfection in this detachment
while in this realm of existence
- but it is our duty as Jedi to continue training
ourselves to do this.
By training, which we will get
ever closer to this asymptotal goal.
</p>

<extx cls="sw">
<p>
"Train yourself to let go of everything you fear to lose."
-- Master Yoda - <dcn>Revenge of the Sith</dcn>
</p>
</extx>

<extx cls="note">
<p>
This practice was also a key part of the practice
of the ancient Stoics.
To this end, there is the high emphasis on
studying the <info ref = "book/epictetus/enchiridion">Enchiridion
of Epictetus</info>.
</p>
</extx>

</lcn>


<lcn>

<p>
The one who has a hot temper does not
run as high a risk of turning to the Dark Side
as the one who denies zir responsibility
to get a grip on zir temper.
So if anyone in the metatemple claims that zir
temper is not serious enough to warrant the effort
of mastering it, remind zim of this.
</p>

<p>
And if someone in the metatemple objects to
doing zir part to control zir temper on the basis
that that's just how zie is -- remind zim that
inborn traits that predispose someone to temper
are a birth condition, and trauma in the past
that makes the temper more unruly are a circumstance
- but refusing to do what one aught to do
in effort to control it is nonetheless a choice,
and that therefore one may be rightly held
accountable for it.
</p>

</lcn>


</sect>
